<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: scotland | Cleanweb UK]]></title>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/categories/scotland/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T11:26:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cleanweb UK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where Cleanweb and Startup Weekend Collide]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/09/27/where-cleanweb-and-startup-weekend-collide/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-27T17:37:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/09/27/where-cleanweb-and-startup-weekend-collide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="margin: 0px 15px; margin-bottom:10px; float: right"><img src="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/images/posts/sw_glasgow.png" alt="startup weekend glasgow"></div>


<p><em>Cleanweb is partnering with <a href="http://glasgow.startupweekend.org">Startup Weekend Glasgow</a> to host one of the very first sustainability-themed Startup Weekends on 25th October at <a href="http://www.citizenm.com/glasgow/societym">CitizenM, Glasgow</a>.</em></p>

<p>In recent years barriers to starting a business have lowered significantly. <a href="#democritizing">In a talk</a> presented at the Stanford Graduate School of Business, author and serial entrepreneur, Steve Blank, dubbed this change the ‘democratisation of entrepreneurship’. In it he discusses the various factors that have lead to this change, such as the cost and speed of product development. If you’ve got an hour it’s very much worth watching, if not, the first ten minutes outline his observations on the trend.</p>

<p>Technology has had a massive part to play in these changes. The Internet has given us reach to greater markets and as incredible as it may seem it is still growing enormously. The ‘open source’ movement now applies to hardware as much software, making it easier for us to prototype physical products. The aid of fabrication labs and hacker-spaces such as <a href="http://www.maklab.co.uk/">Glasgow’s own Maklab</a> (also <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/maklablondon/maklab-london-open-access-digital-fabrication">opening in London</a>) mean you don’t need to own everything to realise your creations. Once you’ve finished product development, small-batch manufacturers like <a href="http://ponoko.com">Ponoko.com</a>, mean you don’t need to order your stock in the hundreds of thousands.</p>

<p>Aside from the entrepreneurship’s new ‘pull factor’, many of us are feeling a ‘push factor’ too. Since the economic crash of 2008 the numbers of self-employed have increased enormously.</p>

<p style = "padding-left:1em; margin-top:1.5em; margin-bottom:1.5em;">

“According to official figures, the number of self-employed people in the UK has risen 374,000 since the start of the financial crisis, reaching 4.2 million in April this year.” – <a href = "http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-22845051">BBC News</a>

</p>


<p>Questionable job security has shifted perspective on the risks of business start-up. Consider a recent graduate faced with a low or unpaid internship. A year spent on a venture (even if it fails) holds far more potential and reward.</p>

<p>With new means at our disposal many of us are aiming to carve out prosperous and resilient futures. A large part of that future prosperity depends on how we treat our planet. Unfortunately, environmental decision making has mostly been a top down affair. Much like starting a business was, involving the few rather than the many.</p>

<p>That’s where the Cleanweb movement comes in. We believe the democratisation of entrepreneurship, increases in technology and innovation can be applied to drive massive changes in sustainability. You don’t need to be a venture capitalist, the head of an NGO, or a hydrogen fuel cell specialist. Your idea to make the walk to work more fun (and drive business to a cafe along the way) could be in the hands of thousands of people. You’d be responsible for reducing greenhouse gases, improving air quality, and perhaps save the high street while you’re at it.</p>

<p>*The best ideas are the simplest, whether it’s making <a href="http://loco2.com">continental rail travel easier</a>, or helping people make decisions about <a href="http://sustainablejohn.com/?p=400">which appliance to buy</a>. We’ll be talking about this, <a href="http://glasgow.startupweekend.org">Startup Weekend</a>, and more at the next <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-Scotland">Cleanweb Meetup in Glasgow</a> on 3rd October, and <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London">in London</a> on 21st October.</p>

<div id = "democritizing">
<iframe width="480" height="360" src="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com//www.youtube.com/embed/n-H7TAcqGko?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleanweb Opens in Scotland]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/03/14/cleanweb-opens-in-scotland/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-14T12:56:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/03/14/cleanweb-opens-in-scotland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="margin: 0px 15px; margin-bottom:10px; float: right"><img src="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/images/posts/cca.jpg" alt="the CCA building from the outside"></div>


<p><em><a href="http://www.cleanweb.org.uk/blog/2012/10/09/mobilizing-developers-to-make-a-better-future/">The call to action</a> for entrepreneurs and developers is being heard ever further. The 22nd March will see <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-Scotland/">the first Cleanweb meetup</a> in Scotland at Glasgow's CCA.</em></p>

<p>In terms of clean-tech, Scotland is a busy place, especially owing to the rich potential of renewable resources in the country. 12 out of Scotland’s 14 universities are engaged in clean-tech research and centres of innovation such as the ECCI provide a hub for this research to reach market market and impact the real world. Recently, the ECCI saw the launch of the Green Tech Meetup, an informal gathering of entrepreneurs and investors.</p>

<p>Politically, energy and environment are devolved issues. This means policies are legislated from Holyrood rather than Westminster. Of note, is the 2009 <a href="http://www.legislation.gov.uk/asp/2009/12/contents">Climate Change Act</a> and the <a href="http://www.scotland.gov.uk/Topics/Environment/waste-and-pollution/Waste-1/wastestrategy">Zero Waste Plan</a>. The Climate Change Act has set a target of reducing greenhouse gas emissions by 80% by 2050, with an interim reduction target of 42% for 2020. The Zero Waste plan set a target of 70% recycling and composting for all waste and a maximum of 5% sent to landfill, both by 2025.</p>

<p>Institutions aside, there are great examples of grass-roots initiatives driving change. Most inspiring, is the story of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eigg#Isle_of_Eigg_Heritage_Trust">the Isle of Eigg</a>. After a community land buy-out, the islanders got to setting up their own electricity grid which is 90% powered from renewable sources.</p>

<p>Like anywhere else in the world, there are still significant barriers to achieving a sustainable society. In the past 10 years, investors in the clean-tech space have become more risk averse and the economic crash hasn't helped either. It's also becoming clearer the extent to which systematic and behavioural change are also required.</p>

<p>Even if you don't believe in the 'techno-fix' (the idea that technology will save us), it's hard to argue technology doesn't shape our behaviour. Consider how much the internet has shaped behaviour in the past ten years. What could happen in the next ten? Taking this into account, it seems as though digital solutions have hardly been put on the menu.</p>

<p>Locally, there is plenty of technical talent to tackle these challenges. The presence of home-grown companies such as <a href="https://www.ewgeco.com/">Ewgeco</a>, <a href="http://www.freeagent.com/">FreeAgent</a>, <a href="http://www.skyscanner.net/">Skyscanner</a> as well as big names such as Amazon, NCR, and Rockstar show there's a healthy community of technically skilled people out there. Many of whom are becoming involved in hacking for social good. Very shortly we'll see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hack_Day">hack-days</a> in <a href="http://learnerjourneydatajam.com/">education</a> and <a href="http://www.nhshackscotland.org.uk/">health</a>. Meanwhile, the activities of the local <a href="http://blog.okfn.org/category/events/okscotland/">Open Knowledge group</a> are connecting the grass-roots with larger institutions.</p>

<p>Encouraging surroundings for our new Cleanweb group. If you'd like to find out more or get involved <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-Scotland/">join us on the 22nd</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
