<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meetup | Cleanweb UK]]></title>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/categories/meetup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T11:26:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cleanweb UK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleanweb September - Energy]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/08/11/cleanweb-September/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T18:06:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/08/11/cleanweb-September</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our next event is about how web technologies are helping to change how we consume energy.</p>

<h3>Schedule</h3>

<h4>7:00 - Introduction and community announcements</h4>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://dynamicdemand.nesta.org.uk/">Dynamic Demand Challenge</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.connectinghomes.co.uk/">Connecting Homes Startup Competition</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Got a request for help with your project? Looking to hire someone who gets the web, and sustainability?_</p>

<p>Let us know at <a href="mailto:info@cleanweb.org.uk">info@cleanweb.org.uk</a>, and we'll help spread the word._</p>

<h4>7:20 -&nbsp;Data Science for Sustainability:&nbsp;<a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/joejk">Joe Kwiatkowski</a> - <a href="http://www.ecofactor.com/">EcoFactor</a></h4>

<p>Data science is increasingly used to improve sustainability, for example improving the efficiency of the&nbsp;electrical grid, informing transport planning, and even reducing the methane emissions from livestock farming. I'll discuss the broad opportunities and challenges of data science in this context, and provide some specific examples the field of automated home energy management. Time permitting, I'll highlight some of the key companies that are in the field, both from Silicon Valley and beyond.</p>

<p>7:40 - Break for refreshments.</p>

<p>Refreshments generously provided by our hosts, Forward.</p>

<h4>8:00 -&nbsp;Reducing PC energy consumption:&nbsp;<a href="http://unop.co.uk/">James Singleton</a> -&nbsp;<a href="http://shutdownscanner.com/">Shutdown Scanner</a></h4>

<p>Reverse engineering an off the shelf home electricity monitor to log data to a Raspberry Pi, replacing PCs with lower power devices and using software to monitor computers left on when not needed.</p>

<h4>8:30 - Internet of Power:&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/digitalenergy53">James Johnston</a> - <a href="http://www.openutility.co.uk/">Open Utility</a></h4>

<p>The current energy system was built in the late 19th century when distributed renewable energy and the Internet did not exist. My vision is to create a completely decentralised ‘Internet of Power’: a peer-to-peer energy network that enables individuals to source their electricity directly from power generators. The talk will suggest how this can be done and outline the technical and commercial challenges that lie ahead.</p>

<h4>9:00 Decamp to <a href="http://www.brewdog.com/bars/camden">BrewDog</a>!</h4>

<h2>Interested?</h2>

<p>As ever, places are limited but free, and you do need to RVSP, so if this sounds interesting to you, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/126235782/">sign up now on our meetup.com page</a>.</p>

<p>If you Lanyrd like us, <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cleanweb-september-energy/">we're also there</a>.</p>

<p>If you are interested in speaking at a future event do get in touch!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleanweb and the Internet of Things: Storified]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/07/23/cleanweb-and-the-internet-of-things-storified/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-23T09:22:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/07/23/cleanweb-and-the-internet-of-things-storified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<script src="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com//storify.com/CleanwebUK/cleanweb-and-the-internet-of-things.js" type="text/javascript" language="javascript"></script>


<p><noscript>[<a href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com//storify.com/CleanwebUK/cleanweb-and-the-internet-of-things" target="_blank">View the story "Cleanweb and the Internet of Things" on Storify</a>]</noscript></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleanweb July - Cleanweb and the Internet of Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/07/17/cleanweb-july/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-17T22:06:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/07/17/cleanweb-july</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="margin: 0px 15px; margin-bottom:10px; float: right"><img src="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/images/posts/arup.jpg" alt="the Arup building"></div>


<p>This month, we're teaming up with the Internet of Things Meetup group, to run an IoT-themed meetup in the <a href="http://www.arup.com/News/2010_04_April/15_Apr_2010_Arup_8_Fitzroy_St_Office_Design.aspx">suitably futuristic green-themed offices of Arup</a>, on <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=8+Fitzroy+Street,+London,+United+Kingdom&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=48.77566,92.724609&amp;oq=8+fit&amp;hnear=8+Fitzroy+St,+London+W1T+4BJ,+United+Kingdom&amp;t=m&amp;z=16">8 Fitzroy Street</a>.</p>

<h2>Schedule</h2>

<h4>6:45 - Doors Open</h4>

<h4>7:00 - Introduction and community announcements</h4>

<p>What is the Internet of Things, and what is the Cleanweb, and why are they interesting together?</p>

<h4>7:10 - Community announcements</h4>

<p>Got a request for help with your project? Looking to hire someone who gets the web, and sustainability?</p>

<p>Let us know at <a href="mailto:info@cleanweb.org">info@cleanweb.org</a>, and we'll help spread the word.</p>

<h4>7:20 - Demand Logic : Data mining to save energy in commercial buildings</h4>

<p><a href="https://www.demandlogic.co.uk/">Joe Short - Demand Logic</a></p>

<p>Joe tells the story of the founding of Demand Logic and outlines some of their recent experience of using data mining, machine learning and visualisations to focus attention on massive energy wastage in commercial buildings.</p>

<h4>7:40 - Break for refreshments.</h4>

<p>Refreshments generously provided by our hosts, Arup.</p>

<h4>8:00 - Working my way off the grid with my Rasberry Pi</h4>

<p><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=38468260">Steve Pike</a> and <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=91442281">Chris Elsmore</a> from <a href="http://www.carbonculture.net/">Carbon Culture</a></p>

<p>Chris and Steve tells the story of hatching a plan to use Raspberry Pis and cheap solar panels to get off the grid, one gadget at a time, and the pitfalls and pratfalls along the way.</p>

<h4>8:30 Sustainability and Transparency in an Internet of Things: Appending open data to physical things to foster more informed purchasing decisions.</h4>

<p><a href="http://jessibaker.co.uk/">Jessi Baker</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.matthussey.co.uk/">Matt Hussey</a> from <a href="http://www.projectprovenance.com/">Provenance</a>.</p>

<p>Provenance tells the true stories of products. It is a platform for transparency and it's built on open data. We believe revealing the truth about how something is made can help us buy better things, both for the environment and for societies near and far.</p>

<h4>9:00 Decamp to the pub!</h4>

<h2>Interested?</h2>

<p>As ever, places are limited but free, and you do need to RVSP, so if this sounds interesting to you, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/120265922/">sign up now on our meetup.com page</a>.</p>

<p>If you Lanyrd like us, <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cleanweb-and-the-internet-of-things/">we're also there</a>.</p>

<p>See you on Monday!</p>

<!-- links -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cleanweb May - Climate Change]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/05/13/cleanweb-may/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-13T22:06:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/05/13/cleanweb-may</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This month, we've got a financial flavour for the monthly meetup, with with a clutch of speakers, either using the financial markets to address climate change, or arm them with better info to make more long term sustainable decisions.</p>

<h3>Venue</h3>

<p>We've also been lent the ultra swanky offices of <a href="http://www.climatechangecapital.com/contact-us/offices/london-uk.aspx">Climate Change Capital</a> for the event, next to City Hall by London Bridge, so in between talks, we'll have a change to admire London's skyline.</p>

<h3>Schedule</h3>

<h4>7:00: Introductions and community announcements</h4>

<p>Got a request for help with your project? Looking to hire someone who gets the web, and sustainability? Let us know.</p>

<h4>7:20 - <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/environment/interactive/2013/apr/19/countries-exposed-carbon-bubble-map">Unburnable Carbon</a>: making the carbon bubble visible</h4>

<p>Robin Houston and Duncan Clark - Kiln / The Guardian</p>

<h4>7:40 - Break, refreshments and mingling</h4>

<p>Refreshments courtesy of Climate Change Capital</p>

<h4>8:00 - <a href="https://www.cdproject.net/en-US/Pages/HomePage.aspx">CDP</a>: Using open data to reduce the emissions of cities</h4>

<p>Conor Riffle - Head of Cities, CDP</p>

<h4>8:40 - <a href="http://www.trillionfund.com">The Trillion Fund</a>: Crowdfunding the rollout of renewables across the globe</h4>

<p>Julia Groves - Managing Director, Trillian Fund</p>

<h4>9:00 - Decamp to the <a href="http://www.drafthouse.co.uk">Draft House Pub</a></h4>

<p>After the talks, we're heading to the Draft House pub, which sports a staggeringly wide selection of beers, and offers some fantastic food.</p>

<h3>Interested?</h3>

<p>As ever, places are limited but free, and you do need to RVSP, so if this sounds interesting to you, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/112033502/">sign up now on our meetup.com page</a>.</p>

<p>If you Lanyrd like us, we're also there <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2013/cleanweb-may-climate-change/">lanyrd</a>.</p>

<h3>Working on something?</h3>

<p>See you in a week!</p>

<!-- links -->



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Data and the Environment]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/open-data-and-the-environment/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T23:59:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/01/07/open-data-and-the-environment</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's the start of a new year, which can only mean one thing new meetup for the new month!</p>

<p>For our first meet up of the year on <strong>Monday 21st Jan</strong>, we'll be looking into the terribly trendy world of Open data, fitting enough, at swanky offices of the <a href="http://theodi.org/">Open Data Institute</a>.</p>

<p>We'll be covering how open data is being used around the world, with speakers from academia, government and startups giving a series of short (15 mins each) talks, showing how people are using it to fight climate change.</p>

<h3>Speakers:</h3>

<ul>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.jacktownsend.net">Jack Townsend, University of Southhampton</a></strong>: Open sustainability: can opening up knowledge save the planet?</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://wearehomely.com">Seb Junemann &amp; Jamie Young, Homely</a></strong>: Using open data to stimulate energy-efficient behaviour</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.london.gov.uk/">Tom Chance, Greater London Authority</a></strong>: Two years of open environmental data releases</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://hiyamaya.wordpress.com/">Maya Forstater</a></strong>: Doing the sustainability math: can open data help us work out 9 billion divided by 1?</p></li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Doors open at 6:30pm, and our first talk begins promptly at 7pm</strong>.</p>

<p>After the talks are finished, we'll be holding a few minutes Q &amp; A
for the speakers, before heading out by 9pm to continuing the conversation outside the ODI, in <a href="http://www.thefoxpublichouse.co.uk">The Fox pub</a>.</p>

<p>Places are limited but free, and you do need to RVSP, so if this sounds interesting to you, <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/92321742/">sign up now on our meetup.com page</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
