<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: london | Cleanweb UK]]></title>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/categories/london/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-02T07:06:44+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cleanweb UK]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/12/02/celebrating-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T06:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2013/12/02/celebrating-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at Cleanweb UK, we've had quite a year. In <a href="">London</a>, we've run a great event every month, on topics as diverse as gaming and finance, and membership has almost reached 600. We've got a new group off the ground in <a href="">Scotland</a>, which has met a few times and had a successful collaboration with <a href="">Startup Weekend</a>.</p>

<p>Now, the end of the year is coming around, and so it's time for something a bit special to celebrate such a great year!</p>

<h2>Lightning Talks</h2>

<p>Because of all of that, <a href="">Cleanweb London in December</a> will be a celebration of our brilliant community; we'll be holding a lightning talks evening, and we want to hear from YOU. What's your big idea? How are <em>you</em> going to change the world? Whether it's something you've already done, something you want to make, or a way in which you're doing things differently, we want you to come along and inspire your community.</p>

<p>We're after 10 lightning talks, 5 minutes each maximum, and if you've never spoken in front of people before, don't be scared - lightning talks are a great way into doing it. It doesn't have to be technical, but if it's about sustainability on the web, we want to hear about it!</p>

<p>Cleanweb London is on <a href="">16th December</a> (only two weeks away), so if you fancy speaking, get in touch via <a href="mailto:info@cleanweb.org.uk">email</a> or <a href="http://twitter.com/cleanwebuk">Twitter</a>.</p>

<p>Of course, the event would be nothing without the audience, and we want it to be a big one, so go and sign up on the <a href="">Meetup page</a> right now and we'll see you there!</p>

<h2>Sponsors</h2>

<p>We're also looking for sponsors for the event to make it a bit more special, so if your company is interested in supporting our fantastic community, please get in touch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Because we don't want to bluescreen the planet]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/ignite-cleanweb-what-a-night/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T23:14:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/ignite-cleanweb-what-a-night</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Thursday 13th September, we ran our first ever Ignite Cleanweb event, at a fantastic venue  generously provided by the lovely people at <a href="http://forwardtechnology.co.uk">Forward</a>.</p>

<p>And to put not too fine a point on it, it seems to have went far better than we dared hope - we wanted to showcase some of the best work happening at the intersection between sustainability and the web, and we had a clutch of speakers doing just that, showing how they were using the web to rethink mobility, mapping, and energy, food and supply chains to name a few of the talks on the night.</p>

<p>But don't just take my word for it - we already <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/72550332/">have enough people saying nice things about the night</a> on the internet for us to feel pretty damn chuffed about the night already.</p>

<p>In particular, <a href="http://sustaination.co/2012/09/cleanweb-the-power-of-software-to-save-the-world/#">Ed Dowding (disclosure - one of the speakers on the night)</a> actually beat us to this post by a full day, and managed to say write something following the announcement of the Cleanweb Manifesto that we couldn't help but quote here about the night:</p>

<blockquote><p>It’s quite brilliant that the internet has come along just at the right time (albeit very much at the 11th hour). It is open, abundant, distributed. It mocks time and space. It brings people together to share and learn and change. It inspires, motivates, and empowers. It makes doing better easier. Of course it does not have all the solutions, but it mediates and sets the tone for many of them.</p>

<p>We are proud to be a part of it.</p>

<p>The presentations were also truly, deeply, brilliantly, emotionally, practically, socially inspiring.</p></blockquote>

<p>If you missed the event, or if you just fancy watching the talks again, you can watch them all on the <a href="http://igniteshow.com/events/ignite-cleanweb">Ignite website</a>, on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUPaWd5mPJEGJK0vLva0AEvRIj35DKl2e">Youtube</a>, or right here:</p>

<iframe width="853" height="480" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLUPaWd5mPJEGJK0vLva0AEvRIj35DKl2e&amp;hl=en_US" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Still want more?</h3>

<p>If you're feeling full of inspiration, and heading to the <a href="http://okfestival.org/">Open Knowledge Festival in Helsinki</a>, there's a <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/81444932/">cleanweb-themed Green Hackathon</a> taking place where you can see what others are doing, and hack on a project yourself.</p>

<p>Alternatively, if you're in London, you might also be interested in our <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/81444932/">next social pub-meet</a>, at that Old Street startup stalwart, the Reliance.</p>

<p>See you there hopefully!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignite Cleanweb Talk Details]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/ignite-cleanweb-talk-details/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T12:05:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/ignite-cleanweb-talk-details</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just 8 days to go until <a href='http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/ignite.html'>Ignite Cleanweb</a> comes to London!</p>

<p>We've nearly finalised the list of talks, and have put the titles and speakers up on our <a href='http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/ignite.html'>Ignite</a> page.</p>

<p>So, come along to <a href='http://forwardtechnology.co.uk/venue'>Forward Technology</a> on Thursday 13th September, and learn how <a href='http://loco2.com'>Loco2</a> took on <em>the European Rail Booking Monster</em>, or maybe how to live <em>Offgrid in the City</em>. How about <em>Good Food, For Everyone, Forever</em>, courtesy of <a href='http://sustaination.co'>Sustaination</a>, or <em>how open hardware can help save energy</em> with <a href='http://openenergymonitor.org/'>OpenEnergyMonitor</a>?</p>

<p>Places are limited, so <a href='http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/72550332/'>register now</a> to make sure you don't miss out! If you can't make it, we'll be streaming live video and posting the talks online afterwards, so you don't have to miss out.</p>

<p>Also, if you're an organisation and would like to buy the beers in the pub afterwards, please <a href='mailto:info@cleanweb.org.uk?subject=Ignite Beers'>get in touch</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Register now for Ignite Cleanweb!]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/register-now-for-ignite-cleanweb/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T22:27:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/register-now-for-ignite-cleanweb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's only a month until <a href='http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/ignite.html'>Ignite Cleanweb</a> hits London!</p>

<p>We've got 12 great talks lined up for you, covering the whole range of cleanweb activity in the UK. Learn how <a href='http://loco2.com'>Loco2</a> and <a href='http://whipcar.com'>WhipCar</a> are using the web to change the face of travel, or, if you fancy something more technical, how to write climate-friendly code and run it in a climate-friendly datacentre.</p>

<p>It's happening the evening of Thursday 13th September, at <a href='http://forwardtechnology.co.uk/venue'>Forward Technology</a> in Camden. With great talks,
good conversation, and a few beers thrown in, it should be a night to remember.</p>

<p>Places are limited, so <a href='http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/72550332/'>register now</a> to make sure you don't miss out!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ignite Cleanweb: Call for presenters]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/ignite-cleanweb-call-for-presenters/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T08:39:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleanweb-uk.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/ignite-cleanweb-call-for-presenters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.cleanweb.org.uk/">Cleanweb UK</a> are excited to announce our first <a href="http://igniteshow.com/">Ignite</a> evening in London, hosted by <a href="http://forwardtechnology.co.uk/venue">Forward Technology</a> on <strong>Thursday 13th September 2012</strong>.</p>

<p><a href="http://igniteshow.com/">Ignite</a> is a geek event that has been held in over 100 cities worldwide. At the events, Ignite presenters share their personal and professional passions, using 20 slides that auto-advance every 15 seconds for a total of just five minutes. Add some beers and interesting conversation, and it should be a night to remember!</p>

<p>The main attraction, however, is YOU! If you've made <em>anything</em> on the web that has a sustainability aspect, let's hear about it! Whether you want to talk about an old project, or a new idea that's still written on a beermat, this is your opportunity to show off to and inspire a roomful of like-minded people.</p>

<p>If you want to present (and we hope you do), then let us know when you <a href="http://www.meetup.com/Cleanweb-London/events/72550332/">RSVP on Meetup</a> and, if you want, add yourself as a speaker on the <a href="http://lanyrd.com/2012/ignite-cleanweb/">Lanyrd page</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
